So, one of my SAS products that I run
every day has been running for over four
years, and it has a very active roadmap.
I have a small team working with me, uh,
two developers and one, uh, customer
support person. And, yeah, it's just it
it's gotten to a really efficient
workflow where we're managing our
roadmap, we are building and shipping
new features, we're fixing bugs, we're
helping customers, and we manage all of
that in a tool called Linear. You may
have heard of it. So, I thought in this
video I would walk through and show you
our actual uh linear project management
setup for my SAS product. We used to use
GitHub issues and although we still use
GitHub today, we don't use the issues
system as our project management tool
anymore. Now, we're using Linear because
it has a really strong integration with
GitHub. But anyway, uh the the product
that I'm talking about is Clarity Flow.
that is a SAS product that I started
back in 2021 and you know it's a good
little product. It's built into uh you
know quite a few features as you can see
uh over the years. So let me kind of
take you behind the scenes and show you
what day-to-day life of uh of managing
this Clarity Flow SAS product looks like
in linear. All right, so here's a look
at Linear. I'm going to uh increase the
screen size so we can dive right into
it. Here's the general view that I hop
into on a daily basis. I usually have
this bookmarked in my browser. And I
like the cananban layout. Of course, you
could switch to uh to like a list mode
as well, but um I really like this
cananban layout. It's showing me
basically this is filtered to the active
issues that are currently happening. I
usually spend most of my time looking at
this um yellow section which is in
progress. These are the issues that my
developer is currently working on. Um,
these are issues that my developer has
finished. These are under what we call
in review. So, these are finished and
they're waiting for me to hop in and
actually review them. In this case, we
are in the middle of building out a a
big new feature. Um, so I'm sort of
waiting for most of the sub features to
be finished before I go in and review
everything. Um, I'll get more into that
workflow in just a minute. Over here on
to-do is the other area that I focus on
a lot and these are this is like the
queue. I really like this concept of
almost all of my work I think of in
terms of a queue. What's happening next?
So whatever is at the top of this queue
is going to be mostly my developer next
task. Some of these are um actually
assigned to me and they've been sitting
in this queue for a long time because I'
I've been slow to get to my queue. But I
can also filter by person. So now I'm
filtered to just the issues that are
assigned to Sandia uh my developer. And
I can see that um her queue is is still
pretty long. And I'm constantly going in
here and I'm I'm sort of like
reshuffling the uh the issues that she's
going to be working on next. That's in
the to-do status. Let me step back a
little bit and um and go into the
settings to show you how we can manage
where is it? Settings. Yeah. Yeah. So,
you can go into your your teams and then
go into issue statuses and automations.
And this is where you can manage um all
of the different issue statuses. So, um
I I pay a lot of visual attention to
these icons. So, like the dotted circle
means that it's sort of in this like
preQ phase. And I have several statuses
here. So, like new, soon, later, and
noted. And then we have sort of like the
next phase of the life cycle of an issue
which is like shaping which means that I
know it's it's soon to be cued for my
developer to work on but I need to spend
time in the shaping process um writing
out the requirements and I'll show you
that in just a minute. And then we have
that to-do phase which I just showed
you. Um that's the long list of of
that's the actual cue of of what what's
on deck. Then we get into actually
working on the issues. So in progress
that's yellow. So, I'm constantly
looking for these yellow icons to see
like, all right, these are the the one,
two, sometimes three issues that are
actually in in progress. Then, we get
into review. So, that means that my
developers finished and now it's ready
for me to review. And then we often have
a lot of issues that I have already
reviewed um but we haven't actually
greenlighted them to go into our deploy
process. So, that I put those into
reviewed and then we have a lot of
issues in ready to deploy or actually we
don't have a lot. We try to have a small
number of issues to deploy but that
means that we've done the review we've
done the internal testing and QA and
it's all ready and so then um it's in
the the batch of issues to you know
merge into our main branch and deploy.
Then once we have deployed we will uh
push it into pending and deployed or
deployed. The difference between these
two is we have already deployed
something to the production app, but we
still need to notify some customers to
say, "Hey, we've fixed that bug or or
hey, we need to um send out a a
newsletter to announce this new
feature." That means it's pending and
deployed. Or if it's completely done,
deployed, already announced, already
told everyone we need to tell, that's in
deployed. We don't really use this one
anymore. Occasionally, we'll have an
issue that we just cancel it. So, we'll
put into into canceled. So that's how
I've like customized all the possible
statuses that a issue can have and
that's what defines
um these columns. If I go back into all
issues and if I actually like zoom out
to all issues, this will include
everything. So you know getting back to
that um how I've started to organize
things I I'll talk a little bit more
about these statuses and how we're using
projects in linear and how we're using
labels. So, you know, at a high level
again, like Clarity Flow is a somewhat
mature product. We're over four years
into its existence. So, we're in this
phase now where we have a lot of past
features. We have some new features that
are on the future roadmap, but most of
our work revolves around managing
feature requests, bugs, and small new
enhancements to existing features. And
so we're constantly receiving um
customer requests and we label those
with the label customer request. I made
it a bright yellow because I try to
focus my attention on the things that
customers are asking for. So anytime a
customer is asking for something, we're
going to um slap the the customer
request label on it. And so then a lot
of my job as the owner and the product
manager here is to spend a lot of time
in these columns. Really, no one else on
the team is is doing this. I'm the one
who focuses on these columns to try to
decide, okay, these are the ones that I
think we should try to get to soon.
These are the ones that we'll get to a
little bit later. And these are noted,
meaning like, all right, I know that
they exist. We still want to have them
documented here in linear, but we're
probably not going to do them anytime
soon. Or maybe we will, but I haven't
decided yet to push it into soon or
later or into shaping. So then we get
into shaping and that's when I'll I'll
take an issue from over here and put it
into into shaping. And as you can see,
there's not much info in here yet.
That's why it's in shaping, meaning this
is an issue that's waiting for me to
write some some notes about it. I'm
still actually a little bit unsure about
this one. Uh but yeah, I haven't uh
gotten to it yet. Let's see this one.
Okay, so here's one. It's a customer
request, and as you can see, several
customers have requested it. Me and uh
Cat, our customer support person, have
gone back and forth and discussed this
uh quite a bit. These are some of the
notes that actually Cat wrote. She's our
customer success person uh and she um
noted them. And so I'm at some point I'm
going to come in here and convert these
notes into hard requirements. I'm going
to get more into that in just a minute
to show you what it looks like once I
get it into the queue for my developer
to to run with. Um, but that's what's
happening in shaping. And frankly, a lot
of these things get kind of stale where
like I might think something is
happening soon, but then it'll sit in
the soon list for for way too long. And
that's probably the case with most of
these things. So, you know, I I try to
come in here every month or two or 3
months and sort of retriage things. But
I'll be completely honest, most of that
kind of falls to the back burner. I'm
I'm spending most of my time h in the
to-do um column. Before I get into the
details on, you know, these like
detailed notes that go into an actual
issue, I want to talk more about some of
the organizational stuff. So, I talked
about the customer request label. The
other label that we use quite a bit, of
course, is the red one that says bug.
So, if we look at, let's see how many
bugs were currently. So, here's one. Um,
this is a bug. We gave it the red bug
label. So, those are really the two
labels that we use a lot. either
customer request or bug. We have
actually a lot of other labels but that
we don't use as much. Um sometimes I'll
use the research label when it's
sometimes I'll have like an issue that's
not really a new feature to build. It's
just a technical research task like give
this some thought or give this some
research. I might slap that one on it.
Um if we're focusing on writing tests,
maybe I'll I'll put that on there.
Sometimes it's a super small issue and
I'll and I'll put the small label on it.
A lot of these labels are old and not
used anymore. So just a few weeks ago
actually or a few couple months ago, we
started actually making use of linear
projects feature and that's these down
here with these like cube icons. In this
product, in this SAS product, we have
quite a few major features and those
features have sub features. So these are
more like areas of the app, right? So,
ClarityFlow, it's a it's a platform for
coaching. So, we have a big
conversations section. We have a a newer
uh forms feature. We have Clarity Flow
Commerce, which is our payments and
Stripe integration. We have appointments
booking. So, for each of these big areas
of the app, we gave it a project. So now
I so that enables me to filter our
entire board down to just the sub
features or bugs or feature requests
that are related to in this case our
appointment setting feature. Right? So
actually right now we're we're currently
building a new feature that is still
under the umbrella of the appointments
feature. So we've already shipped the
big appointments scheduling feature.
Next, we're going to be shipping
recurring appointments. The ability to
sell and book a recurring appointment
thing the way that a coach would
typically sell like coaching engagements
every week or every month. They can sell
these recurring um appointments. And
it's actually a super complex feature to
build. So, um all of that is happening
under the appointments project. If I
want to hop over to the commerce, that's
another huge feature in our app. It's
it's a Stripe integration. It's the
ability to sell and have product pages
and subscriptions and manage customers,
manage purchases. So, that's a huge
project. And as you can see, all of
these sub features or all these little
issues are related to our um commerce
feature. So, we've started doing that
and I've informed my team that we want
every single issue, no matter what it
is, to fall into one of these projects.
Occasionally we'll use this like
miscellaneous project for things that
you know just don't really fit into
anything or maybe they're just related
to like our clarity flow checkout
process itself or something like that.
But yeah, we're using these these
projects quite a bit. Okay, now let's
dig into the issues themselves. I want
to show you what it looks like uh behind
the scenes, my interaction with my team
and and how we how we work together.
First, let's focus on new features. So,
as I said, we are currently in the
process of building a new feature. This
is our recurring appointments feature.
So, I'm going to pull open this issue.
So, this is one piece of this big new
feature. And I've broken the the big new
feature into probably like 10 to 12
different issues. And as you can see, I
this is already shaped. So, I spent the
time to write all of these checklists.
Um, so everything that you see here was
written by me. Um, I give a quick
overview and then I have a lot of these
checklists and subchecklists, lots of
technical uh, instructions um, giving
like labels and my developer and I we
sort of have some like shorthand on on
how we like to describe different
interface elements to each other. Um,
and as you can see these are all checked
off because this is now in review which
means uh, Sandy has already finished all
these items. I really like to use these
check these checkable things so that I
can see exactly which items uh she is
finished. So if I back out and look at
one of these. Yeah. So this one is in
progress. And down here here's like the
checklist for that. You can see only
some of them are checked and some of
them are not. That's how I can hop in at
any point in any day to see what exactly
is the current progress without needing
to bug my developer to say, "Hey, where
are we at on this or that?" You know, um
I can just see right in the checklist.
It's very easy. Um, let me get back into
one of these issues which is now ready
for review. So that's the top section.
That's like the description where I put
the the checklist. If I scroll down,
this is the comment section. A lot of
activity happens in our comments
section. And this is actually one of the
reasons why I chose to switch over to
using linear away and moving away from
using GitHub issues. GitHub did not have
the ability to have threaded comments.
So one way we use comments in linear is
you know we have the single comment and
then I can reply underneath it. And what
that allows us to do is when it's
finished as it is here you know um Sandy
was clarifying some requirements and
then I gave her a quick uh answer. She
thumb she gave me a thumbs up to say
like got it. Um, and so even though this
is three weeks ago, what I probably
should have done is I can resolve this
and I can hide it away. And I love that
we can, and I'm actually going to keep
it open in case she still needs it. But,
you know, all these individual comment
threads, we can we can just, you know,
resolve them and hide them away. Okay.
So, uh, here's a good example of a piece
of a feature which we've already
shipped. This is our tasks feature where
my developer and I had uh lots of back
and forth conversation about how this
feature should work and the underlying
logic that goes into it. And this is
where linear comments really um shine.
As I said, we can expand and collapse
the comments when we're done looking at
them. Um but here's a good case where my
developer sort of raised, let's see, one
two different issues in one comment. And
what I'd like to do here is then
separate these out to separate comments,
which is exactly what I did here. So she
raised the issues here. I collapsed it
and then I started a separate comment
for each one. So here's, you know, issue
one and we do a lot of like quoting of
each other to say this is the thing that
I'm going to reply to. So she asked this
question and then I gave this response
about how we should think about the
logic around issue one. And then my
developer always gives me a reaction to
just confirm to me like yes, got it. I
don't need a message to say like yes, I
got it. Because that's going to be like
another message that goes into my inbox
which I don't need. But I do want to see
like saw it, got it on it. Like so we
use these thumb thumbs up emojis a lot.
So keeping it separate, keeping one
issue or one question to one comment
allows me to give a response. Maybe
we're going to continue to to to hash
this one question out, but when it's
finished, we can resolve that and then
we can move on to the other issue. So
again, like this is the se the second
issue and I started a separate comment
thread. Here it is. Um there's actually
a little bit more to it. And and then
here we we sort of go back and forth. As
you can see, we are quoting each other
um quite a bit. You know, this is where
communic async communication especially
textbased communication or technical
discussions, technical product
discussions, this is how my my developer
and I collaborate. I actually think that
this is a better way than going on a
call and talking it through because then
a lot of that a lot of that nuance a lot
of these details get lost or getting
forgot get forgotten about. Whereas here
we have it all documented in highly
technical, highly specific comment
threads that my developer or I can
always refer back to. And we are often
referring back like many weeks, many
months out into the future. We're we're
referring back to technical discussions
that we had months ago. And it's all
logged here in really easy to find um
comment threads. again like we're I'm
giving some some examples for different
scenarios and and how we should be
handling each of these scenarios and and
the logic that that goes into them. Um
sometimes you know she's referencing a
block of code or um you know and then
finally uh we get to okay this is all
completed and here's the PR. So that's
what it looks like when we are kind of
like hashing out a new feature that
we're actively building. The other thing
that we do quite a bit is taking in bug
reports and customer requests. And I
want to show you what those look like
cuz they happen they they look a little
bit different in linear. So let me go
back into all of our active issues and
um okay so here is an example of a bug
that a customer reported. So what
happened here was the customer
originally uh reported the the issue.
Actually they used ClarityFlow to report
the issue to us. Sometimes they use
Clarity Flow, sometimes they use Help
Scout, our our help desk software that
we use. Um but our support person took
the customer report and then and then
she replicated the issue to confirm like
yes this is a bug she sees it too and
then uh she wrote up this issue um which
includes the details about what he was
trying to do um and she said that she
tried to figure it out um and she
included the the customer's video that
he shared. What we also always always do
both when it's a bug report and when
it's a customer request is we add the
link. You can do uh command K uh link um
yeah add link and you can just add a
link to a help desk issue or uh or or
like a clarity flow link or or you know
wherever the customer reported it. We
always do that so that later when we
come around and fix this issue, we have
the the quick link that points to that
person's um message thread where we can
get back to them and say, "Hey, it's
fixed." Right? So, um Cat reported this
issue or Cat filed this issue in linear.
She actually tagged me. This was 6
months ago. So, since then, we've
switched it over so that uh you know,
Sandy will just, you know, hop in and
immediately receive it from cat and I
don't even really need to touch it. Uh
but Sandy Sandy our developer will go in
and um identify the issue. Uh she fixed
it. She made a PR and um and then uh I
moved it over to ready to deploy and she
deployed it to production. Um and then
from here uh cat will take it and go
back to the customer and say hey your
your issue has been fixed. So that's
typically what a bug fix looks like. So
um here is one of those like big
features that we received a lot of
customer requests for. It's it's tasks
like the ability to assign to-dos to
clients in your message threads in
ClarityFlow. Um what we usually do uh
anytime we have this customer request
label on it, you can expect that it
should have at least one link to a
customer who has requested that feature.
So these are links that point to like
help scout conversations. Sometimes
they're pointing to clarity flow
conversations. Um, and uh, you know,
we've probably have had even many more
requests than this. These were just the
ones that we happened to remember to to
link to. Um and when customer when
feature requests come repeatedly, the
benefit of organizing all these requests
using projects and using labels and
using very uh detailed specific titles
is that it makes it easy for our support
person or myself to find the existing
issue that we have and add that
customer's uh voice to the list of
links. The reason why this is really
helpful is first when it comes time for
me to go in and shape the feature and
design it and decide like what
functionality we're going to have. I
spend a lot of time going through and
reading these these uh request help
threads from customers to really get a
sense on what exactly they were trying
to do in terms of like the job to be
done. And that's what will inform me to
figure out how we should scope out and
shape an issue. And then most
importantly is later when we come back
and we have finished a feature and you
can see some of these happen like over
many months sometimes across years. We
circle back and we send a personal note
to each of these customers to say hey
that feature that you wrote us in and
and asked for we've shipped it. It's
live. Check it out. Here you go. We'll
probably do like a larger announcement
of every feature as well, but we always
send a personal message to each
individual customer who ever asked for a
feature and we have them all linked up
here right from from the linear ticket.
So, um that's really really helpful.
What else? So, I use the favorites thing
in the in the left side um to get to a
lot of the most commonly viewed views.
So, uh, you know, again, I I basically
put every project that we have in a
favorite so that I can easily get to
that get to that view. And then I also
put people. So, um, there's myself and
then Sandy is our like primary developer
right now. And so, I'm always clicking
on her name to be able to, um, just
filter all the issues by to see like
what is Sandy working on and what's in
her queue. And of course, I I probably
should have led with this at the start
of the video, but the inbox. So, usually
every morning when I'm coming into
Linear to check the status, the very
first place that I'm going to go to is
this inbox in the top left. One
complaint that I have about Linear is
that they don't send regular email
notifications. Or they they do, but I
don't like how they do the digest thing
where they gather multiple issues and
multiple comments into a single email in
my regular email inbox. I'm not a fan of
that. I would much prefer to have
separate
individual email messages from any apps
that send me messages so that I can deal
with them like regular emails. like one
message needs one reply and I might I
might need to reply to that later. So,
I'm going to leave that one message
unread. Um whereas other messages I can
just work through. Linear just does not
have that individual separate
notification for each individual
comment. Yes, it leads to lots more
emails, but I can I can then process
those emails one by one. So, that's
unfortunate, but the good thing is that
Linear itself has a really good inbox of
its own. So, I've actually stopped using
Linear's email notifications and instead
I just have a daily habit of every
single morning I'm coming into Linear
and the first place I go is the inbox. I
can see how many new messages. I usually
leave it in this mode where I'm not
showing my red messages, but I can
toggle that on if I need to get into
older stuff, but mostly I'm just looking
at the new stuff. I like how they can
show me that this isn't even a message.
This is just a thumbs up. So that that's
something that like I know that Sandy
didn't actually send me a new comment
that I need to read. All I need to do is
like click it. I can see that she's
thumbmed up it and that's all I need to
do. Done. I also like how in this view
the inbox will show me the current
status. It'll show me the status of the
issue that the comment is on. So I can
see that these are all yellow, which
means these are all comments on issues
that are currently in progress. And that
tells me that these are probably
questions that are blockers. What most
likely happened here, and I haven't even
read this one yet, is she ran into a
blocker or she ran into a question. This
is still in progress. So, I need to read
it and give her an answer so that she
can move forward. And if I go into my
red messages, you can see a lot of these
are green like like this one, I could I
could see, you know, she finished this
uh this part of the feature where she
completed the task. Um, so her comment
to me was just to tell me that she
completed it and she recorded a video to
show me uh the the the task which is
very helpful. But I can see here that
the status of that comment or the status
of the issue where that comment is it's
green which means like it's not as
urgent in my mind uh because that's just
a message to tell me that it's complete.
Whereas these are messages on in
progress things which are probably
blockers. So, I'm going to prioritize
that and get right back to my developer
as quickly as I can so that we can move
forward and ship faster. Um, so that's
how I manage the inbox and uh yeah,
overall that's as much as I could show
you on how we use Linear to manage my
SAS application. Now, the other app that
I'm using every single day is Cursor.
That is the tool that I use for all of
my coding and using AI to uh to make
code changes in my projects. So I'm
constantly bouncing back between linear
and cursor. Linear is where we manage
our uh code related projects between me
and my small team. And cursor is where I
spend my time coding and building
products. And so if you want to see an
inside look into how I'm using cursor
every day and how I'm using AI to help
me uh you know ship my products faster,
check out my other video that I just did
on how I'm using cursor to build
products. I'll see you there.